Matthias Bachfischer

CURRICULUM VITAE

Munich, Germany

■ bachfischer.matthias@gmail.com | • Bachfischer | • Bachfischer

Summary_

Currently studying Data Science at the University of Melbourne - worked previously as an IT Architect at BCG Platinion. Strong technical background in Machine & Deep Learning as well as a deep business in digital transformation topics. Interested in working on challenging problems with real-world impact.

Education

The University of Melbourne

Melbourne, Australia

M.Sc. IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2020 - Nov. 2021

- Undertook lectures on advanced concepts in Statistics and Computer Science
- · Conducted research on frameworks and techniques for Machine Learning & Deep Learning

Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule Regensburg

Regensburg, German

B.Sc. IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Oct. 2014 - Feb. 2018

- · Undertook lectures on various programming languages (Java, Javascript etc.), databases, computer networks and operating systems
- Conducted research on applications for Machine Learning in Intrusion Detection Systems
- Title of bachelor thesis: Success Factors in Business-Managed IT

Universidad de Buenos Aires

Buenos Aires, Argentino

LICENCIATURA EN ANÁLISIS DE SISTEMAS

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2016

• Semester abroad as an exchange student in the Faculty of Engineering (Facultad de Ingeniería)

Industrie- und Handelskammer Regensburg

Regensburg, German

IT SPECIALIST (SYSTEM INTEGRATION)

• Professional training as part of the integrated degree program at KRONES AG

Jul. 2013 - Jan. 2017

Work Experience _____

BCG Platinion GmbH

Munich, Germany

VISITING ASSOCIATE & IT ARCHITECT

Jul. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Advised various companies from Industrial Goods & Automotive sector on digital transformation & IT strategy
- · Designed, built, and implemented digital platforms and IT architectures using Information technology

King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Thuwal, Saudi-Arabia

VISITING STUDENT

Apr. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- · Conducted research on Machine Learning & Deep Learning techniques to classify toxic comments in online social networks
- Implemented a dataset-driven search engine for scientific publications

KRONES AG Neutraubling, Germany

INTEGRATED DEGREE PROGRAM - INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Jul. 2013 - Feb. 2018

- Implemented a Big Data platform based on Apache Hadoop
- · Supported various business departments at KRONES with their Software and Requirements Engineering activities

KRONES do Brasil São Paulo, Brazil

Internship

Aug. 2015 - Sept. 2015

- Performed the migration of a stand-alone e-mail system to centrally hosted system based on MS Exchange
- Trained the local IT staff to carry out IT support activities related to email and mobile device management

Honors & Awards

2016 **Scholarship**, German Academic Scholarship Foundation

Bonn, Germany

2020 **Study Abroad Scholarship**, German Academic Exchange Service

Bonn, Germany



Implementation of a real-time data analytics platform for connected cars

• Design and implementation of a cloud-based real-time data analytics platform for a leading German automotive OEM to process and analyze streaming data from connected cars in real-time (AWS)

Design of a target IT architecture to enable analytics use cases in Manufacturing

• Design of a target IT architecture to enable implementation of Manufacturing analytics use cases for a large automotive supplier

Publications

Success Factors in Business-Managed IT

Berlin, German

SKILL - STUDIERENDENKONFERENZ INFORMATIK

Sept. 2018

Presented a research paper from a case study analysis of critical success factors in Business-Managed IT (i.e. Shadow-IT systems that are
operated overtly and with support of the IT organization)

Offensive Comment Classification on German Language Microposts

Vienna, Austri

GERMEVAL 2018 - SHARED TASK ON THE IDENTIFICATION OF OFFENSIVE LANGUAGE

Sept. 2018

 Presented the participation of the KAUST Laboratory for Machine Intelligence and kNowledge Engineering (MINE) at the GermEval 2018 shared task (research paper + poster)

Academic Experience

Java Programming Lecture - Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule Regensburg

Regensburg, German

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2018

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Teaching assistant for Java Programming lecture ("Programming 2")
- Responsible for weekly programming exercises with first-year students

Languages.

German, maternal language
English, excellent command
Spanish, very good command
Portuguese, good command
Arabic, working knowledge
Chinese, basic knowledge

Extracurricular Activity

International Negotiating Skills

Regensburg, Germany

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Oct. 2015 - Jul. 2017

· Lectures and seminars on theoretical frameworks for cross-cultural studies and advice on how to act in an international environment

Campus Asyl - Association to support refugees in Germany

Regensburg, German

MENTOR

Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Mentoring and assistance for refugees studying for a university degree at OTH Regensburg